<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><transcript><text start="0.32" dur="5.373">Hello everybody and welcome to this lesson
in the Pioneer School Extra about casting</text><text start="5.694" dur="5.39">out demons. Last time I laid the
foundation where we spoke about how</text><text start="11.085" dur="5.157">Jesus drove out demons and the 12 and
the 70 and now it is for everyone who</text><text start="16.242" dur="5.102">believes and these signs will follow those who believe.
In my name they shall cast</text><text start="21.345" dur="4.616">out demons. This time I am going to
build on this and do it a little more</text><text start="25.962" dur="5.062">practical. We are going to look at some
examples of book of Acts 8 where you</text><text start="31.025" dur="6.162">read about Philip in Samaria. How Philip
came to Samaria and unclean spirits</text><text start="37.188" dur="5.046">cried out with a loud voice and came out
of people and lame people were healed</text><text start="42.235" dur="4.383">and were walking. We believe Jesus is the
same yesterday and today and this is what</text><text start="46.619" dur="5.574">we should experience today. And I&amp;#39;m going
in this program to show a lot of clips.</text><text start="52.194" dur="6.662">This is one clip from Hannover in Germany
a few days ago where you see this.</text><text start="58.857" dur="6.468">This woman came to me and the demon
started to scream and look what happened,</text><text start="82.841" dur="4.2">And then she could walk without
crutches, she came with crutches,</text><text start="87.042" dur="9.312">and now you see she walks (clapping and
applause) and a big joy came to the city</text><text start="96.355" dur="4.849">as we read in the book of Acts 8. We are
looking at the book of Acts 19, about</text><text start="101.205" dur="5.014">different things and then we are trying to
put it all together how when it is casting</text><text start="106.22" dur="3.857">out demons, how it is renewing the
mind and how it is all about LOVE.</text><text start="110.078" dur="5.222">Because the love of God can really set us
free and I am using my own example how</text><text start="115.301" dur="5.21">God had set me free, and use other
examples and then I ended up praying for</text><text start="120.512" dur="5.146">you out there who need freedom, who need deliverance.
So welcome to this lesson</text><text start="125.659" dur="2.639">about casting out demons.
God bless you.</text><text start="141.622" dur="2.479">Yes, Hello everybody
we are back again,</text><text start="144.102" dur="5.753">with a new lesson about casting out demons.
Last time I went through some of</text><text start="149.856" dur="5.941">the things you see here behind me about
what Jesus did, how He cast out demons,</text><text start="155.798" dur="4.885">how He called the 12 to do it, how the
70 did it and now it is for everyone who</text><text start="160.684" dur="5.109">believes. And also we spoke about last
time there was religious people who came</text><text start="165.794" dur="5.523">with different things saying this is not
for today and we should be careful and</text><text start="171.318" dur="5.848">so on and so on. In this lesson I am going
to be a little more practical, I am going</text><text start="177.167" dur="5.516">to continue where I ended. But be a little
more practical. How does this work?, how</text><text start="182.684" dur="5.764">does it work with casting out demons with
renewing the mind, with using the gospel?</text><text start="188.449" dur="4.41">So if you have not seen the last lesson I
encourage you to start with that because</text><text start="192.86" dur="5.425">it will give you an overview of what I am
going to talk about now. I am also going</text><text start="198.286" dur="5.212">to show you some exciting videos in this
lesson about where you see how demons</text><text start="203.499" dur="4.634">are leaving and what it looks like. The
whole idea is that you will experience</text><text start="208.134" dur="5.553">freedom and that you out there, you will
go out and cast out demons, because</text><text start="213.688" dur="4.679">this is what we are called for. So it is
going to be really interesting I have</text><text start="218.368" dur="5.335">really looked forward to this. I will
just start with pray, “God thank you</text><text start="223.704" dur="4.736">for everything you are doing. Thank you
Jesus for you have given us authority to</text><text start="228.441" dur="4.062">go out and cast out demons and heal the sick.
You have called us to preach the</text><text start="232.504" dur="5.245">gospel. I pray that you will come and use
this lesson to open our eyes and our ears</text><text start="237.75" dur="5.83">and help us to set us free so we can live
in the power, live the life you have for</text><text start="243.581" dur="4.49">us. Come with your Holy Spirit and help
me to share what you want me to share.</text><text start="248.072" dur="7.505">In the name of Jesus. Amen. Ok, cast
out demons, first I want to share</text><text start="255.578" dur="5.542">some testimonies because a lot of things
are happening right now. Actually I just</text><text start="261.122" dur="6.163">got told today that I am going to be on
Danish TV, the biggest TV show in Denmark</text><text start="267.286" dur="5.788">in a few days. Monday evening. Monday
evening I will be live on TV in Denmark,</text><text start="273.075" dur="6.077">on the biggest TV station at 7 o&amp;#39;clock,
where I will talk about casting out demons</text><text start="279.153" dur="7.945">because later on Monday evening at 8;30
on TV 2 in Denmark they are airing a</text><text start="287.099" dur="5.649">program and I am part of it. And in that
program it is also about casting out</text><text start="292.749" dur="6.012">demons. Because a few months ago there
came a host to me who followed me out</text><text start="298.762" dur="4.768">on the street who wanted to see how we
were doing out on the street when it came</text><text start="303.531" dur="3.887">to praying for people and when it came
to actual deliverance and casting</text><text start="307.419" dur="4.473">out of demons. Because this is something
people are talking about today, about</text><text start="311.893" dur="4.63">What is it? It is weird for people, is
it really demons today and what does it</text><text start="316.524" dur="7.4">look like when people are set free?
So Monday evening live tv programme</text><text start="323.925" dur="4.677">and Monday evening later I am going to
be on this programme, they are going to</text><text start="328.603" dur="5.042">send this programme with me. I just want
to share a clip from the live programme,</text><text start="333.646" dur="5.005">this is going to be on Danish tv, this is
a clip that is going to be sent where you</text><text start="338.652" dur="5.933">see me out on the street a few months
ago where we stood out on the street</text><text start="344.586" dur="5.365">and there was a woman there who looked
at us and I asked can we pray for you?</text><text start="349.952" dur="6.134">and she said yes and she came to us and I
asked her what her problem was and her</text><text start="356.087" dur="5.519">problem was she had asthma and she had
been operated two times on her heart, so</text><text start="361.607" dur="4.389">she had been shocked (electrical shock) in
her heart two times through her operation</text><text start="365.997" dur="5.099">and I prayed for her and what you are
going to see in this clip is the way I</text><text start="371.097" dur="5.324">often pray for people is, I hold their
hands and get them to relax and then</text><text start="376.446" dur="4.355">And then I pray, lead them to a pray and
pray for God to come and set them free.</text><text start="380.988" dur="6.809">Sometimes we see healing where it just
like, healing happens other times we see</text><text start="387.822" dur="6.459">a demon manifested like a deliverance is
taking place and what you see hear is</text><text start="394.306" dur="4.17">the way she reacts, you can see she
started to go back and she started to</text><text start="398.477" dur="4">react. And you can see in this way it
is clear to see that there is something</text><text start="402.502" dur="5.063">demonic, so I will just show it, it is in
Danish but I will try to translate what</text><text start="411.548" dur="8.871">they are saying “Go now….go now”. And
you can see she is reacting, she</text><text start="420.444" dur="4.287">is going backwards and something is
happening, I don’t close my eyes,</text><text start="424.732" dur="4.381">I look really close to their eyes and
see what is happening, and (video)</text><text start="431.164" dur="4.892">something left there, I felt, and then I
prayed for the Holy Spirit to come over her</text><text start="438.713" dur="4.054">I said “You can feel something?” (woman)
“Yea, I went back, what was that?”</text><text start="443.719" dur="4.73">(woman) “I don’t know what it was?” (Torben)
And I said “Yes, something reacted in you</text><text start="448.474" dur="3.605">it was fear and something left
you, try to breathe again</text><text start="452.278" dur="7.753">look ather now (video) (woman) “Wow, it is so different
from before” (Torben) “Try again, can you feel it is gone?”</text><text start="461.85" dur="6.73">(woman) “Where do I find you in some months?” (Torben)
“It is easy, it is about Jesus, it is not about me”</text><text start="468.605" dur="4.895">So this is a small clip that is going
to be part of our programme in Denmark.</text><text start="474.628" dur="3.743">We are called to cast out demons,
we should not be afraid of it,</text><text start="478.396" dur="4.013">we should not be afraid of it doing it in
public, we should not be afraid of doing it</text><text start="483.023" dur="4.309">on tv, we should not be afraid
of doing it out on the street.</text><text start="487.512" dur="3.693">There has often been a lot of fear in the
church when it comes to the demonic,</text><text start="491.71" dur="5.124">but you see in the bible that they did
not hide it away, they did not take the</text><text start="496.859" dur="4.023">demonic and say ‘wow’ it is a demon we
have to be careful, we have to put it in,</text><text start="500.907" dur="4.888">close a door inside a room where nobody
saw it, ‘no’ in the bible we see</text><text start="505.82" dur="5.999">that it happened publicly, out there and
we have got authority not only to heal</text><text start="511.844" dur="5.224">the sick but also to cast out demons.
With that woman, when I prayed for her</text><text start="517.11" dur="5.819">I thought it was a healing needed but as
soon as I prayed the Holy Spirit came</text><text start="522.953" dur="4.017">over her and the demon started to
manifest and she got set free.</text><text start="526.971" dur="5.501">And this is now going to come out to
many people and I am going to have to</text><text start="532.497" dur="4.956">change to be on a live programme and
tell more about what God is doing.</text><text start="537.961" dur="5.794">First we are going to experience many
religious people and non -believers and</text><text start="543.85" dur="5.064">people who don’t believe in what we are
doing but we are also going to meet many</text><text start="548.993" dur="3.999">people who actually believe in it. When
we talk about the religious people,</text><text start="553.017" dur="5.474">last time we saw some of the things they
were saying to try to create fear in us</text><text start="558.516" dur="5.704">when it comes to casting out demons and
one of the examples has been used a lot</text><text start="564.245" dur="7.288">to create fear in us who believe to say
that it is dangerous we should not cast</text><text start="571.558" dur="7.847">out demons, it is from Acts 19. Acts
19 verse 13 we read that there were</text><text start="579.43" dur="9.186">‘Seven sons of Sceva, and we read here
in Acts 19;13 that there was some Jewish</text><text start="588.641" dur="5.672">exorcists who took upon themselves to call
the name of the Lord Jesus over those</text><text start="594.338" dur="6.801">who were demon possessed, and we read
there what happened, and what happened?</text><text start="601.464" dur="9.226">the demon answered “Jesus I know and
Paul I know about, but who are you?” and</text><text start="610.715" dur="5.847">then the man with the demon leapt on them,
hit them, took their clothes off so</text><text start="616.587" dur="7.985">those seven sons ran away naked. Maybe
you have heard that story in church?</text><text start="624.597" dur="4.996">I have heard it a few times, and I often
heard it as an example to ‘be careful,</text><text start="629.618" dur="5.914">be careful, be careful, here was somebody
who tried to use the name of Jesus but</text><text start="635.533" dur="6.196">they were new in it, they didn’t have the
experience therefore the guy with the</text><text start="641.754" dur="6.116">demon leapt on them and hit them so they
needed to flee naked from that place.</text><text start="649.148" dur="5.603">Maybe you have heard that also as an
example to be scared and be afraid when</text><text start="654.776" dur="5.47">it comes to casting out demons, but this
is not talking about somebody who is</text><text start="660.435" dur="6.431">born again, this is not talking about
seven sons of sceva who have the</text><text start="666.89" dur="5.009">Holy Spirit and who believe in Jesus,
this is talking about somebody</text><text start="671.925" dur="5.513">who does not have the Spirit inside
of them, who do not know Jesus.</text><text start="677.439" dur="6.513">And we know that for sure by reading the
text in context, every time you read</text><text start="683.977" dur="4.609">a text always read it in context. Try
to read what is written before and</text><text start="688.611" dur="5.603">what is written after the text because
when you see what is written before and</text><text start="694.238" dur="3.245">after this text you will
understand what it is all about.</text><text start="698.103" dur="8.323">After this text where we read that the
seven sons run away naked we read this</text><text start="706.427" dur="6.612">‘When this’ you know ‘this’ the news of
the seven sons became known to the Jews</text><text start="713.078" dur="8.089">and Greeks living in Ephesus they were
all seized with fear and the name of the</text><text start="721.192" dur="7.784">Lord Jesus was held in high honour. So
what is happening here? ‘here we have a</text><text start="729.001" dur="5.1">man with a demon who leapt upon seven
people who tried to cast out the demon</text><text start="734.126" dur="6.436">and they fled away naked. The next
thing that happened was a big</text><text start="740.587" dur="6.794">fear came upon the people and they
worshipped Jesus, they worshipped God.</text><text start="747.642" dur="6.701">It doesn’t make sense, why would they
worship God, why would they lift up the</text><text start="754.368" dur="7.434">name of Jesus and worship Jesus when a
demon had just leapt on seven people and</text><text start="761.827" dur="5.8">took their clothes off them so they needed to flee?
It would not make sense if</text><text start="767.652" dur="5.198">a born again Christian today came in and
tried to cast out a demon and that demon</text><text start="772.875" dur="4.847">leapt on the and beat them so they need
to run away and people in the church hear</text><text start="777.753" dur="4.465">that they would not say ‘thank you
Jesus you are so amazing, your name is</text><text start="782.243" dur="6.955">glorified, and so amazing, ‘no’. Why
did they worship God? because they</text><text start="789.357" dur="5.639">knew that those people were not believers,
they were not born again and they</text><text start="795.017" dur="7.519">worshipped God because of what happened before that,
because a few words before, that we read this</text><text start="803.572" dur="4.528">‘God did extraordinary miracles
through Paul, so even the</text><text start="808.125" dur="7.076">handkerchiefs and aprons that had touched
him were taken to those who were ill and</text><text start="815.258" dur="6.087">the illness was cured and the demons,
the evil spirits left them Acts 19:11.</text><text start="821.37" dur="6.619">So what do? We read here a verse before?
We read that God did amazing miracles</text><text start="828.014" dur="6.102">through Paul, the took some of the clothes
he wore that had touched him, they took</text><text start="834.148" dur="4.73">the clothes, went to people who people who
were sick, went to people who had demons</text><text start="838.903" dur="6.969">and as soon as they laid their clothes on
them, the demon left them, and then what</text><text start="845.897" dur="7.728">happened? Those seven sons who were
exorcists, who tried to cast out demons</text><text start="853.65" dur="5.482">but did not know Jesus, they saw the
miracles by the hands of Paul so they went</text><text start="859.157" dur="8.117">out and tried to cast the demon out in
the name of Jesus who Paul knew, and</text><text start="867.299" dur="6.199">the demon leapt on them and people saw
the difference between those new age</text><text start="873.499" dur="6.999">alternative, non beleivers who tried to
cast out demons and then the real true</text><text start="880.499" dur="5.707">life Paul, and then what was the result
of that the name of Jesus was lifted up</text><text start="886.237" dur="8.036">and many came and openly confessed
what they had done and a number</text><text start="894.274" dur="4.709">who had practiced sorcery and brought
brought their scrolls together and</text><text start="899.064" dur="6.575">burned it properly Acts 19:18. So
here we see the full story, the full</text><text start="905.64" dur="6.958">story is ‘not’ that we should be afraid
of casting out demons because this is</text><text start="912.623" dur="4.276">not born again beleivers. The full story
is that by the name of Jesus we have</text><text start="916.924" dur="6.815">authority and people saw the power
through the hands of Paul, then there</text><text start="923.764" dur="5.913">were some people who practiced sorcery who
tried to use the name of Jesus but it</text><text start="929.756" dur="6.197">did not work good, and people there saw
the difference between those people who</text><text start="935.978" dur="3.894">practiced sorcery and the real life,
(change ‘life to believer?) and what</text><text start="939.92" dur="5.46">happened, many of them came afterward
and confessed what they had done and</text><text start="945.444" dur="6.374">brought their things and burned them in
public ‘why work with sorcery when we</text><text start="951.819" dur="6.396">have the real thing? Why work with false
gods when we have the name of Jesus?</text><text start="958.295" dur="4.841">When Jesus is alive. And this
is the same we are seeing today</text><text start="963.161" dur="5.982">when we are starting to see the power of
God how the Holy Spirit is working, people</text><text start="969.168" dur="5.943">bring their things and burn it in public,
people bring their things and destroy</text><text start="975.136" dur="4.904">them, they don’t want anything to do with
sorcery anymore and that is what we saw</text><text start="980.065" dur="4.035">in Germany a few weeks ago. We were in
Berlin a few weeks ago where we visited</text><text start="984.125" dur="5.351">a family, it was the second time we were
there and we saw the second time we</text><text start="989.501" dur="3.299">were there a demon came out of people.
There came new people and they got set</text><text start="992.801" dur="5.454">free from demons, they fell on the floor
and the demon left them and people</text><text start="998.256" dur="5.065">got healed and set free. And that
family also had a lot of things</text><text start="1003.322" dur="4.869">like we read here in Acts 19, with
sorcery and things they had been using</text><text start="1008.216" dur="5.299">so they gathered all of those things
they had into the garden and you can see</text><text start="1013.54" dur="4.482">(camera image) there is a lot of idols
here that they had, what did they do?</text><text start="1018.308" dur="1.581">They destroyed it all.</text><text start="1020.252" dur="2.262">This is the before
and after picture.</text><text start="1022.578" dur="6.672">like this, and then they destroyed it.
Why? Because they saw the real life,</text><text start="1029.505" dur="1.872">They saw what it&amp;#39;s all about and</text><text start="1031.42" dur="5.119">This is what we need to do today,
we need to see the power of God.</text><text start="1036.594" dur="2.992">we should not be afraid to
cast out demons because</text><text start="1039.611" dur="6.531">like here Paul did it out there on the
street publicly there were people where</text><text start="1046.143" dur="5.58">demons left them, there were people who
saw it and they tried to do the same but</text><text start="1051.724" dur="6.083">they couldn’t because there is only power
in the name of Jesus and the result of</text><text start="1057.808" dur="4.934">that was that many repented, why?
Because people want the real stuff.</text><text start="1063.171" dur="7.919">Ok, we see Jesus drove out demons, he
called the 12 to do it, the 70, now it</text><text start="1071.091" dur="5.918">is for everyone who believes, it is for
you and me and I want to come with</text><text start="1077.034" dur="5.69">an example more from the bible the
book of Acts and this is with Philip,</text><text start="1083.184" dur="8.76">the book of Acts chapter 8, we read this
about Philip, he proclaimed Christ to</text><text start="1091.945" dur="6.048">them and we need to do the same
proclaim Christ, but we know the</text><text start="1098.018" dur="5.276">kingdom of God is not words only it is
power so proclaim Christ the crowds</text><text start="1103.319" dur="8.831">with one accord paid attention to what
was being said by Philip ‘why?’ because</text><text start="1112.175" dur="7.796">they saw and when they heard him
and saw the signs that he did.</text><text start="1120.415" dur="5.389">I put it down here. Don&amp;#39;t know if people can see it.
But this is what we read here.</text><text start="1125.907" dur="5.444">these signs follow those
who believe ‘in my</text><text start="1131.352" dur="5.608">name they shall cast out demons, they
shall lay there hands on the sick and</text><text start="1136.996" dur="4.49">they shall get healed ‘this was a
sign as I spoke about last time that</text><text start="1141.487" dur="4.508">followed those people who believe.
And what do we see?</text><text start="1146.02" dur="6.925">Philip he went out and people listened
in one accord to what he said. ‘why?</text><text start="1152.97" dur="7.527">When they saw the signs he did,
and Philip was not one of 12.</text><text start="1160.568" dur="5.347">He was not one of the 70, Philip was
a guy who was filled with the Spirit</text><text start="1165.94" dur="4.689">like you and me should be.
What was the sign they saw?</text><text start="1172.082" dur="8.532">‘For unclean spirits crying out with
a loud voice came out of many who</text><text start="1180.639" dur="5.731">had them, and many who were paralysed
and lame were healed, so there was much</text><text start="1186.395" dur="6.07">joy in the city Acts 8:7. This is what
we read with Philip, that Philip came to</text><text start="1192.49" dur="6.506">Samaria and these signs follow those who
believe so people listened to Philip,</text><text start="1199.736" dur="6.268">he did not speak like a Pharisee, he did
not just speak with words but you saw</text><text start="1206.029" dur="3.054">the Holy Spirit. You saw how
the Spirit of God moved</text><text start="1209.132" dur="6.607">through Philip, they listened and saw
the signs, what signs? Those signs that</text><text start="1215.764" dur="5.65">follow those who believe? That many
with unclean spirits got set free and</text><text start="1221.439" dur="8.086">many lame were healed and we see
here that they came out with a loud</text><text start="1229.55" dur="6.304">voice, this is often what happened.
Do we truly believe? ‘as I have said</text><text start="1235.879" dur="6.01">before in the 20 lessons, do we truly
believe that Jesus is the same yesterday,</text><text start="1241.914" dur="6.109">today and forever? If you said yes then
you also believe that the Holy Spirit is</text><text start="1248.048" dur="6.788">the same yesterday, today and for ever,
and the book of Acts is not about the</text><text start="1254.861" dur="6.982">first 12 apostles, it is a book where you
get a look into the diary of the early</text><text start="1261.868" dur="3.483">church. As I say I think in lesson ‘Three’
(The book of Acts) in the Pioneer</text><text start="1265.376" dur="5.486">School. So the book of Acts gives us a
picture of how the early church was</text><text start="1270.887" dur="5.147">working and if the Holy Spirit is the
same, we should be the same today,</text><text start="1276.732" dur="4.954">we should not just go out and heal the
sick we should also go out and cast</text><text start="1281.711" dur="7.188">out demons. And sometimes it is quiet, and
sometimes it is with a big loud voice</text><text start="1288.924" dur="4.455">and sometimes lame people walk and people
are getting healed and this is our</text><text start="1293.404" dur="6.116">desire to see the same and we saw it
almost a little picture of this a few</text><text start="1299.545" dur="5.761">weeks ago we were in Hannover in
Germany and I want you to see this</text><text start="1305.331" dur="5.64">video it is really amazing. We
were doing an open air in Germany</text><text start="1311.624" dur="10.552">and in this open air a woman came to me,
there was 700 people at the open air and</text><text start="1322.201" dur="5.768">a woman came and before I even started
to pray for her she started to manifest</text><text start="1328.854" dur="4.598">and what you see here you don’t see so
clear in the picture but she came with a</text><text start="1333.492" dur="6.815">cane, she was walking with a crutch and
she had a problem walking so she came</text><text start="1340.978" dur="9.839">and when she came you almost see like
Philip here that the demons came</text><text start="1350.842" dur="7.079">out with a loud voice and the lame could walk.
So this is from Hannover</text><text start="1357.946" dur="5.475">(video) it is only 30 seconds and try
to listen to what the demon was saying</text><text start="1363.422" dur="4.035">here “because I don’t want to go!”
and you hear it are you ready,</text><text start="1370.02" dur="2.875">(Torben) in the name of Jesus….
(demon) ‘oh!…’oh!…oh! …</text><text start="1372.896" dur="2.966">(demon)’I will not go’ …I will
not go!” you are too strong.</text><text start="1375.863" dur="2.354">(Torben) “be quiet!” be quiet!”
“Come out!” “come out!”</text><text start="1378.218" dur="6.467">(demon) “I am going!….I am going! I am
going, I’m going I am going..….Ahh…..</text><text start="1384.686" dur="1.668">(Torben) “Come out!” I command
you “let her go!” come out!”</text><text start="1390.839" dur="4.948">(Torben) “Hi, come up…..try to walk,
how is it now…(clapping and cheering)</text><text start="1395.788" dur="5.493">(woman) Walking without crutches,
(more clapping and cheering)</text><text start="1401.282" dur="5.358">Hallelujah! and here you see a picture,
a picture of the book of Acts 8 like</text><text start="1406.665" dur="3.79">Philip in Samaria, we were just in
Hannover in Germany out there in</text><text start="1410.456" dur="4.833">public a woman came with a cane, a
problem walking but what happened</text><text start="1415.29" dur="5.43">the demon was screaming ‘ahh! And
started to manifest but by the</text><text start="1420.721" dur="4.764">name of Jesus, by the authority
that demon went out.</text><text start="1425.906" dur="6.213">And I want to say when I do this teaching
I don’t want to go into a lot of details,</text><text start="1432.59" dur="4.02">people ask sometimes, ‘o where do demons come from?
‘I need to know’ and how</text><text start="1436.635" dur="5.148">do they look?.... and so on and so on… To
be honest I don’t care how demons look,</text><text start="1442.116" dur="3.797">I think there is a reason we don’t see
them because if we saw them I think</text><text start="1445.914" dur="5.218">we maybe be scared. I just
know one thing, Jesus has</text><text start="1451.133" dur="5.219">commanded me to cast out demons, and
I love Jesus I want to obey him and</text><text start="1456.377" dur="7.218">we need authority. And sometimes the
more you know about the details the</text><text start="1463.82" dur="6.095">more difficult it is to believe. For
example if you pray for somebody</text><text start="1469.94" dur="5.647">with a broken arm, if you in your head
start to imagine now those bones go</text><text start="1475.612" dur="4.742">together and how with those sinues and
bones go together when I am praying,</text><text start="1480.4" dur="6.28">does it look like this? The more you
try to imagine with your head the more</text><text start="1486.705" dur="6.333">difficulty it will be to believe it. But
if you just accept it like this is the</text><text start="1493.039" dur="5.545">truth, I don’t want to understand it,
I don’t want to know exactly how and</text><text start="1498.609" dur="7.943">how it looks, I just love Jesus and do
it, then you will see a breakthrough and</text><text start="1506.577" dur="3.885">you see it here with demons, we cast
demons out every week, and sometimes</text><text start="1510.487" dur="3.933">becomes stronger and stronger and we
have seen amazing clips and amazing</text><text start="1514.445" dur="5.274">things where people get set free, and I
come down to the simple stuff again.</text><text start="1521.407" dur="8.193">In Matthew 17 you read that there was a
guy who had a son who had a demon and</text><text start="1529.625" dur="6.054">they brought that son to Jesus disciples
and Jesus disciples could not cast out</text><text start="1535.704" dur="8.745">that demon, when Jesus came he rebuked the
disciples for their lack of faith and</text><text start="1544.474" dur="5.784">set that boy free. And then he told them
later that kind is only driven out by</text><text start="1550.283" dur="4.02">prayer and fasting, we are not talking
about that special kind of demons,</text><text start="1554.412" dur="5.669">‘no’ we are talking about that unbelief’
that spirit of unbelief that was</text><text start="1560.106" dur="4">in the disciples Because you
don’t have to go through</text><text start="1564.196" dur="5.562">praying and fasting to cast out special
demons, demons are all the same,</text><text start="1569.783" dur="4.411">we have all the authority in heaven and
earth to cast them out cast out demons.</text><text start="1574.882" dur="6.49">Our problem is our lack of faith, our
unbelief, and sometimes there we need</text><text start="1581.397" dur="6.374">to pray and fast for us to be set free
from that unbelief that lack of faith.</text><text start="1588.82" dur="6.765">And when that is gone in our life, then
we have authority, so the more I see</text><text start="1595.639" dur="5.051">the fruits of what the Pioneer School
does and the teaching and what we see</text><text start="1600.882" dur="7.458">is’ the more it comes down to is ‘that
simple, simple faith, you don’t need to</text><text start="1608.365" dur="4.71">know a lot of details, you just need
to take authority and then do it.</text><text start="1613.1" dur="6.011">Know that Jesus died on the cross, he
has the victory, he rose up again,</text><text start="1619.136" dur="4.539">he went to heaven and he sent his holy
spirit down here. now it is you and</text><text start="1623.676" dur="5.21">me who are sent here in Christ place
as his body to continue the good work.</text><text start="1628.911" dur="5.428">He has all the authority in heaven and
earth and he has given that to us so we</text><text start="1634.364" dur="5.191">can now go out in the name of Jesus
to cast out demons, heal the sick and</text><text start="1639.58" dur="4.614">proclaim the kingdom of God, and it is
that simple faith, I hope this teaching</text><text start="1644.219" dur="4.456">will give to you. A question?
can Christians have demons?</text><text start="1648.7" dur="6.589">This is always something people ask ‘can
Christians have demons? It is interesting,</text><text start="1655.314" dur="5.817">if you go to the bible in Luke and see
in Luke the first demon Jesus cast out,</text><text start="1661.132" dur="5.068">it was in the synagogue, it was actually
in the synagogue he cast out the first</text><text start="1666.225" dur="6.741">demon ‘in the church’. So he came to
the synagogue and there a man with an</text><text start="1672.991" dur="5.726">unclean demon started to manifest and
he cast it out. The same we see today</text><text start="1678.742" dur="4.831">there are people in church who
start to manifest who have demons.</text><text start="1684.795" dur="4.399">When people say ‘Christians can’t have
demons I think ‘people don’t know what</text><text start="1689.319" dur="6.414">demons are causing and what a demon is,
without going into a lot of details here</text><text start="1695.758" dur="6.843">in Luke chapter 11 as I spoke about last
time you read that Jesus cast out a demon</text><text start="1702.626" dur="9.363">that was mute and when that demon that was
mute had come out of that person the mute</text><text start="1712.014" dur="7.826">man spoke and everybody was amazed, so
here there came a guy to Jesus who could</text><text start="1719.865" dur="6.669">not speak, he had a sickness, his sickness
was that he was mute, he could not speak.</text><text start="1726.559" dur="7.611">His sickness was caused by a demon, a
mute demon so when Jesus cast out that</text><text start="1734.195" dur="7.244">mute demon, when that demon was out of
him that man who was before mute could</text><text start="1741.464" dur="6.853">now speak, he was healed. So in
this case you see that this demon</text><text start="1748.342" dur="5.749">was a demon that caused him to not speak.
There are other demons where</text><text start="1754.116" dur="5.46">people have sickness that is caused by
demons, it could be deafness, mute,</text><text start="1759.96" dur="6.351">Jesus healed a blind guy by casting out
a demon and the blind guy could see,</text><text start="1766.336" dur="6.538">so in his case it was a demon that caused
that sickness, I don’t say it is the same</text><text start="1772.899" dur="3.505">every time because you also read that
Jesus healed the sick where it was not</text><text start="1776.429" dur="5.316">a demon he cast out he just ‘the blind’
where it was not a demon he just laid</text><text start="1781.77" dur="2.681">hands on the blind person
and they could see.</text><text start="1784.967" dur="8.449">But imagine that this is that demon and
this demon is a mute demon and I am</text><text start="1793.441" dur="5.245">a non-believer and I have a mute demon in
me so I cannot speak or I have a blind</text><text start="1798.711" dur="5.798">demon I cannot see or have a demon, an
unclean spirit in me or I have a demon</text><text start="1804.535" dur="7.04">that causes me to be paralysed or other things.
What happens if we believe that</text><text start="1811.6" dur="7.218">Christians cannot have demons? then we
believe in that second that somebody</text><text start="1818.842" dur="6.127">becomes a Christian born again, that
demon is out of there and therefore</text><text start="1824.994" dur="5.187">they are healed. But do we see this?
Do we see this in the</text><text start="1830.205" dur="6.758">church today that when people enter into
Christ, when they come to Christ right</text><text start="1836.988" dur="5.863">away that sickness has left? In
many places we don’t see that,</text><text start="1843.356" dur="5.002">I think it should be like that, we see it
more and more when people get baptised</text><text start="1848.383" dur="4.94">to Christ right away those demons are
leaving and they are getting healed they</text><text start="1853.348" dur="5.037">are getting set free so we see
it more and more and more.</text><text start="1858.533" dur="5.912">I just shared a testimony with 37 people
who got baptised a few days ago with</text><text start="1864.47" dur="5.714">somebody I spoke with from Italy and
they got convinced and they had people</text><text start="1870.209" dur="4.968">who had an eating disorder and sickness,
when they came out of the water they got</text><text start="1875.202" dur="5.369">set free and they got healed. So we
see it more and more, but it is not</text><text start="1880.596" dur="5.219">something we normally see or have been
seeing in the church. Because in the</text><text start="1885.84" dur="5.127">church today we see many sick people
therefore we also see many sick people</text><text start="1890.992" dur="6.858">who have demons, we see many believers
who have demons. If you ask me if a</text><text start="1897.875" dur="7.538">Christian have demons? yes. Should it be like that?
No. I believe that in the early</text><text start="1905.438" dur="4.848">church they taught a different gospel from
what we heard today, a radical gospel</text><text start="1910.311" dur="6.83">about repentance and denying yourself
and turning away from your sin and then</text><text start="1917.166" dur="4.01">when they got baptised in water to Jesus
Christ it’s not just a symbol, it was</text><text start="1921.201" dur="4.227">radical I die with Christ I rise up with
Christ and in that there is deliverance</text><text start="1925.453" dur="4.664">taking place and then they received the
Holy Spirit and they start a new life.</text><text start="1930.315" dur="5.098">I believe it was what they saw, or like
the book of Acts 8 where Philip came</text><text start="1935.438" dur="5.945">to Samaria and the demons already left
and people already got healed so when</text><text start="1941.409" dur="4.869">they later got baptised in water those
demons were already gone and the sick</text><text start="1946.303" dur="6.188">were already healed so therefore yes they
did not see a lot of Christians with</text><text start="1952.516" dur="5.451">a lot of demons. But today
we have a church where many</text><text start="1957.992" dur="7.356">people inside church are not born again.
They are not fully born again, they have</text><text start="1965.373" dur="3.305">not understood what repentance is,
about baptism in water, about the</text><text start="1968.703" dur="5.077">Holy Spirit, so do I believe Christians
should have demons ‘no’ I don’t believe</text><text start="1973.805" dur="3.617">Christians should get divorced and
remarried and so on again and again,</text><text start="1977.447" dur="4.251">I don’t believe Christians should live in sin.
I do not believe Christians should</text><text start="1981.723" dur="4.28">go after being rich and living their own
life, no’ I do not believe that Christians</text><text start="1986.028" dur="5.668">should do this and this and this but we
are living in a time where we see many</text><text start="1991.722" dur="5.75">people inside church who call themselves
Christians and some of those need</text><text start="1997.497" dur="7.138">deliverance. But what do we then do when
there is a demon?, how do we cast out</text><text start="2004.66" dur="7.118">that demon? What I normally do is,
sometimes it comes automatically,</text><text start="2011.803" dur="5.987">sometimes you go to somebody and you start
to talk and right away you just see</text><text start="2017.815" dur="6.269">there is a demon or you start to pray and
they start to manifest and you see there</text><text start="2024.109" dur="4.339">is a demon, so when you see there is a
demon you just cast out that demon,</text><text start="2028.473" dur="6.024">other times we don’t know if there is a
demon or not and I will talk about that.</text><text start="2035.236" dur="8.21">First I want to show a clip here, this
was from a few days ago here in Aalborg</text><text start="2043.684" dur="5.216">where we are, where we had a kick-start.
A few days ago when we had a kick-start</text><text start="2048.926" dur="4.42">I took people up to demonstrate how
to pray for people as we often to and</text><text start="2053.371" dur="4.201">demonstrate how to talk to people and I
took a few people up and I stood with</text><text start="2057.598" dur="6.375">a woman and I explained when you go to
somebody you stop and smile and you</text><text start="2063.998" dur="5.75">relax, you don’t do like this ‘aaahhh’
you just very nicely smile’ and go to</text><text start="2069.774" dur="5.561">them and say ‘hey, excuse me can I talk to you?
‘hey can I ask you a question?</text><text start="2075.36" dur="4.314">Are you sick? Can we pray for you? So
this is what I wanted to demonstrate.</text><text start="2080.25" dur="4.821">But what happened here ‘we see it more
and more is when I came to her and said</text><text start="2085.096" dur="6.576">“hey, excuse me” I didn’t have time to say
more because as soon as I came close to</text><text start="2091.697" dur="5.758">her and said “excuse me” everyone saw
it was a demon because she started to</text><text start="2097.48" dur="6.098">scream and fell down and the demon was
manifesting and this woman there in front</text><text start="2103.603" dur="5.43">of everybody got set free from a demon and
I want to show a clip here. Are you ready?</text><text start="2109.059" dur="3.056">So it’s not a good quality but here I am.
(Torben points to the clip on the phone)</text><text start="2112.519" dur="5.786">and here you can see this woman there is
the woman I go to, to demonstrate how to</text><text start="2118.33" dur="4.768">stop people and say excuse me can I
pray for you but this is what happened</text><text start="2126.292" dur="1.388">(video sound…”Excuse me can…..
(woman starts to scream and falls to</text><text start="2127.681" dur="2.283">floor ‘screams!) (Torben) ok
it’s not always like that’</text><text start="2129.989" dur="2.914">‘come out! Go, go, go,
go!… (woman)Screaming….</text><text start="2132.951" dur="5.117">(Torben) Go! Go! Go! …go right now in the
name of Jesus! I command this spirit leave</text><text start="2138.069" dur="1.169">(woman)screaming…making different
sounds (Torben) Come out!!</text><text start="2139.263" dur="14.968">And there, there was some false tongues
and different things then it left, yea.</text><text start="2154.537" dur="4.095">So that was a little clip, but in this
case what happened here, we go to</text><text start="2158.657" dur="6.383">somebody and as soon as we stop, as soon
as we talk with them something is reacting</text><text start="2165.918" dur="5.559">I would say the more we live with Jesus
the closer we come into him and the more</text><text start="2171.502" dur="5.67">authority we recognise the authority we
have, the more we will see this, the more</text><text start="2177.197" dur="5.303">we will see the demons manifest before we
come to them, as soon as we talk to them.</text><text start="2182.525" dur="6.861">And we have lots of stories where people
come here to us and feel the manifestation</text><text start="2189.411" dur="6.965">and things reacting already, so this
is what sometimes happens, what often</text><text start="2196.401" dur="6.886">happens is that we are not sure if the
person has a demon and there what</text><text start="2203.312" dur="5.329">we do is start to talk with them and
when I meet a person I have a video here</text><text start="2208.666" dur="4.873">I want to show it was from New Zealand
where there came a guy and when I spoke</text><text start="2213.564" dur="6.276">to him he said that he had a problem with
the Holy Spirit, he had a lot of fear and</text><text start="2219.865" dur="3.946">it was not easy for him to pray in tongues
and he was really afraid because he came</text><text start="2223.836" dur="6.312">from a very, very, religious background
and he felt there was something in him</text><text start="2230.173" dur="3.988">that reacted against this freedom
and against the Holy Spirit.</text><text start="2234.971" dur="6.829">So by talking with him and hearing what
he said I can then say ‘ok I don’t think</text><text start="2241.825" dur="6.177">this is just a renewing of the mind, and
I think it’s not just a question of the</text><text start="2248.027" dur="3.652">gospel here I think actually here (cast
out demons) it is something demonic.</text><text start="2252.295" dur="5.335">So what do I do? I take his hands and
pray with him and then I lead him to a</text><text start="2257.654" dur="3.923">prayer this is often what I where he also
at the same time repent of that wrong</text><text start="2261.602" dur="7.886">thought and religious spirit and when we
do that, we just commanded that spirit to</text><text start="2269.514" dur="5.272">go, often even before we see a
manifestation and I encourage you to try</text><text start="2274.81" dur="4.816">that ‘pray for them and then say “spirit
come out!” “go! Go! Religious spirit I</text><text start="2279.651" dur="5.426">command you, I command you religious
spirit” ….like Jesus, he said there that</text><text start="2285.102" dur="5.043">‘this man he had a problem and the
problem was he was mute so he called</text><text start="2290.17" dur="4.404">the mute spirit to go. If I meet somebody
who says I have a problem with depression,</text><text start="2295.012" dur="4.889">I often say “you spirit of depression go
right now!” if there is a problem with</text><text start="2299.926" dur="4.842">fear “you spirit of fear go right now!”
if they have a problem with sickness and</text><text start="2304.793" dur="4.087">moving around in the body “you
spirit of sickness go right now!”</text><text start="2308.905" dur="4.985">This guy he had a problem with a religious
spirit and fear and other things and I say</text><text start="2313.915" dur="4.705">“you religious spirit, you spirit of fear
I command you to leave right now!” and</text><text start="2318.645" dur="3.986">when you do that and speak, speak, speak,
speak, what happens often is that when</text><text start="2322.656" dur="4.899">you take authority and start to
speak to that issue, that demon,</text><text start="2327.992" dur="8.082">they start to react. And I said last time
sometimes the reaction is ‘exhale’ just</text><text start="2336.099" dur="4.891">a breath and the demon is out. Other
times it is a little more like you</text><text start="2341.015" dur="7.228">see in this video here (video clip) (T)
“Go out now in the name of Jesus!”</text><text start="2348.268" dur="4.377">“I command last thing go!”
“spirit go!” “go! Go! Go!</text><text start="2352.689" dur="6.706">As you can see I just take authority
and command it to go, (T) “come out!”</text><text start="2359.42" dur="2.097">(man) loud groaning! (T) “go!” (man)
“I just felt that something has been</text><text start="2369.641" dur="5.907">lifted and I felt free, I felt the peace
of God again, I felt that ‘yea Lord…</text><text start="2375.573" dur="2.665">I thank you, I thank you
for setting me free.</text><text start="2379.629" dur="4.541">So again here, here is an example where
you saw and there are so many videos</text><text start="2384.195" dur="4.608">with that and in our movie on YouTube, I
encourage you to just see some of the</text><text start="2388.828" dur="5.801">videos, so what do we do? Sometimes
demons just manifest and when you see</text><text start="2394.654" dur="3.888">the demon you just say ‘come out in the
name of Jesus. You don’t have to know</text><text start="2398.567" dur="6.434">why the demon is there? You don’t have
to know how many, you don’t have to make</text><text start="2405.002" dur="5.075">it complicated. There are a lot of videos
on YouTube where people do weird things.</text><text start="2410.102" dur="4.001">To be honest, where people are talking
with the demon and interviewing the</text><text start="2414.128" dur="3.972">demon, I don’t see that. I don’t see that
in the bible and actually I don’t like it</text><text start="2418.622" dur="5.116">When demons are speaking, Jesus spoke back
to them, but very often He said ‘shut up!</text><text start="2424.534" dur="6.004">…he said “be quiet! Come out now!” He
did not go in with a dialogue to ask</text><text start="2431.704" dur="2.736">‘demon why are you there? Are
you allowed to be there?</text><text start="2434.465" dur="3.681">And what has that person done? He
didn’t go into a lot of things.</text><text start="2438.171" dur="4.993">He just said “be quiet come out now!”
One time he asked “how many are you?”</text><text start="2443.189" dur="3.281">and then he heard how many there was and
he cast every one of them out at the</text><text start="2446.495" dur="7.059">same time, but he never went into go in a dialogue.
And I think the problem today</text><text start="2453.579" dur="7.767">is that we cannot trust demons, demons are liars.
It was different when Jesus asked</text><text start="2461.371" dur="6.779">how many are you? because Jesus was the
son of God, he knew the truth, he knows</text><text start="2468.175" dur="4.885">everything you cannot lie to Jesus but you
can lie to us, because we don’t know the</text><text start="2473.085" dur="3.401">whole truth, Jesus knows the truth,
he is the truth, we are not.</text><text start="2477.058" dur="4.577">So I have seen a video on utube where
people are teaching about the spirits</text><text start="2481.66" dur="4.426">around where they are into ‘you demon
why did you come and where do you come</text><text start="2486.111" dur="4.584">from and so on and so on and so on, I don’t
like that because I don’t trust what</text><text start="2490.72" dur="7.24">those demons are saying first thing, another
thing, if we take and start to interview and</text><text start="2497.985" dur="6.053">talk with the demon we forget that there
is a person behind that deliverance and</text><text start="2504.063" dur="5.037">that person, it is a big thing for them
to experience the demon is speaking</text><text start="2509.125" dur="4.605">through them. I have met people who
have went through a deliverance where</text><text start="2513.755" dur="5.091">they interviewed the demon almost and
spoke with the demon and made it become</text><text start="2518.871" dur="5.452">a long, long, long deliverance and yes
maybe that person got set free in the end</text><text start="2525.213" dur="5.436">but that person now has a lot of problems
with fear afterwards because to experience</text><text start="2530.674" dur="4.044">demons taking over and speaking through
your body is not a good experience for</text><text start="2534.765" dur="6.248">that person so therefore I believe we should
do it fast and quick, not go through a lot of</text><text start="2541.037" dur="6.267">things, Just take the authority and so on.
People ask me sometimes why do I shout?</text><text start="2547.743" dur="4.236">Sometimes I shout because sometimes I
don’t want the people to hear the demon,</text><text start="2552.004" dur="5.02">the demon is shouting so I shout louder or
other times I shout because to be honest</text><text start="2557.127" dur="6.06">sometimes I don’t want to listen to my
fear, I can have a little fear sometimes</text><text start="2563.945" dur="5.223">and I don’t want to listen to it so
therefore I shout I take authority. I know</text><text start="2569.193" dur="7.354">I am not heard because of my loud voice
but if a dog is coming inside and really</text><text start="2576.572" dur="7.574">dirty you would not say ‘dog…can you
go out please….the dog would not obey</text><text start="2584.378" dur="6.184">But when you say, “come out now! Go out!”
the dog knows that you really mean it,</text><text start="2591.29" dur="7.117">the same way with the demons, if you just…
demons go..out…the demons don’t listen</text><text start="2598.432" dur="5.637">but if you say “demon come out!” but you
don’t have to scream, you can say it in a</text><text start="2604.094" dur="6.408">way with authority so that the
demon know that they have to go.</text><text start="2611.125" dur="5.717">Before I go there, other question people
ask is what about the return of the</text><text start="2616.867" dur="5.72">unclean spirit that we read about in Matthew 12?
That when Jesus said if a</text><text start="2622.612" dur="5.072">demon has come out of somebody ‘an
unclean spirit’ they will go around and</text><text start="2627.709" dur="5.638">if that house is empty they will come back
with 7 other demons and people sometimes</text><text start="2633.372" dur="4.06">use this example to say you are not
allowed to cast demons out of non-</text><text start="2637.457" dur="3.877">believers or they need to have the Holy
Spirit otherwise those demons will</text><text start="2641.359" dur="9.069">come back. First thing, when Jesus said
that in Matthew 12 he did not say it as a</text><text start="2650.453" dur="6.39">teaching how to cast out demons, he did
not say it to somebody who had just got</text><text start="2656.868" dur="5.771">set free from a demon, he just said it as
a truth, this is what sometimes happens,</text><text start="2663.327" dur="5.559">but we see again and again they set many,
many people free from demons and they</text><text start="2668.911" dur="6.312">never used that verse to those people
who are set free, we don’t see it.</text><text start="2675.505" dur="5.617">Another thing, if Jesus is saying there
that when a demon has come out of</text><text start="2681.147" dur="3.566">people, if people are not filled with the
Holy Spirit that demon will come back,</text><text start="2685.858" dur="8.476">remember that none of those people Jesus
cast the demons from could receive the</text><text start="2694.359" dur="7.45">Holy Spirit, no one, no one, because there
was no Holy Spirit given on earth at that</text><text start="2701.834" dur="4.759">time Jesus was walking here. So when
he cast out a demon some of those</text><text start="2706.618" dur="5.857">people should wait maybe three years
before they were able to receive the</text><text start="2712.5" dur="6.25">Holy Spirit. So it did not hinder Jesus
in casting out those demons knowing that</text><text start="2718.775" dur="3.916">those people could not receive the Holy
Spirit and maybe will not receive the</text><text start="2722.716" dur="5.915">Holy Spirit. The same this verse should
not hinder us in just going out to cast</text><text start="2728.656" dur="8.279">out demons but yes we believe that if
you first are set free and go back it</text><text start="2736.96" dur="5.16">can be worse but this is not only with
demons he is talking about sin, he is</text><text start="2742.145" dur="5.091">talking about sickness, he is talking
about everything because in John 5:14</text><text start="2747.319" dur="4.211">we read that Jesus healed a guy who
was paralysed, he had been paralysed</text><text start="2751.554" dur="5.779">for 39 years and he just healed that guy
who was paralysed. Jesus did not say</text><text start="2757.358" dur="5.527">anything to him he just healed him.
Later on he met him in the temple</text><text start="2762.91" dur="7.824">and when he met him again he said “See
you are ‘well, go and sin no more</text><text start="2770.759" dur="6.105">so nothing worse may happen to you.
So here Jesus said to someone who was</text><text start="2776.889" dur="6.078">paralysed who got healed “go sin no more
so nothing worse will happen to you.</text><text start="2786.29" dur="6.826">What we are called to do is to heal the
sick, to cast out demons, sometimes you</text><text start="2793.141" dur="5.282">felt that after they have got set free
that maybe you should say to them</text><text start="2798.448" dur="4.81">“hey…you have to stop sinning now,
you have to turn away from your life</text><text start="2803.283" dur="4.38">style otherwise it is going to be worse”.
Sometimes you feel you should say,</text><text start="2808.007" dur="5.956">sometimes you feel you should not
say it like we read in the bible.</text><text start="2815.02" dur="6.274">So lets’ put it all together, we have
now spoke about how Jesus drove out</text><text start="2821.319" dur="5.51">demons, the 12 did it, the 70 did it and
these signs follow those who believe</text><text start="2826.854" dur="4.463">and we saw with Philip that he was one
of those believers and they listened to</text><text start="2831.359" dur="4.93">what he said when they saw the signs
that followed him, what signs was this</text><text start="2836.29" dur="5.058">‘many with unclean spirits got set free
and many sick got healed, this is the</text><text start="2841.349" dur="6.383">same for you and me today, we have authority.
You don’t need to know a lot,</text><text start="2848.125" dur="4.239">you just need to know that Jesus has
done it on the cross and you can do it.</text><text start="2852.365" dur="5.566">You don’t need to know why that
demon is there, how many there is,</text><text start="2857.932" dur="5.269">you don’t need to go into details.
If you meet somebody who starts to</text><text start="2863.202" dur="4.248">react as soon as you come there you
know there is a demon and there you</text><text start="2867.451" dur="4.978">just take authority and you call
out and command that demon to go,</text><text start="2872.43" dur="3.534">sometimes it is like a cough, and
you just see they are free and</text><text start="2875.965" dur="6.133">you know they are free. Other times
they are relaxed, and you are not</text><text start="2882.099" dur="5.674">sure so you ask them ‘how are you?
do you feel you are free? ‘yes’…or</text><text start="2887.774" dur="4.009">‘no….i feel there is a little more’
‘ok we will pray a little more.</text><text start="2891.784" dur="6.054">And you pray and you command it to go.
We have been given authority</text><text start="2897.839" dur="6.711">to cast out demons, we don’t need to
ask permission we just go and do it.</text><text start="2904.551" dur="7.068">When that is said, ‘it is not everything
that is demonic as I said last time</text><text start="2911.691" dur="7.998">‘demons we cast out’ ‘mind we renew’.
We do not cast out the mind and try to</text><text start="2919.69" dur="4.942">renew the spirit. We cast out the spirit
and renew the mind, and as I said last</text><text start="2924.633" dur="4.385">time sometimes it is not enough
sometimes we need the gospel and</text><text start="2929.019" dur="6.182">I tried to put it all together
and explain how I use this.</text><text start="2935.202" dur="4.423">When demons are manifesting by
talking with them or when you start</text><text start="2939.626" dur="4.392">to pray for sickness and the demons is
manifesting you just take authority</text><text start="2944.019" dur="4.813">and cast it out. When people are
coming to you and saying ‘can you</text><text start="2948.833" dur="5.211">pray for me I have a problem? Often
what you can do is you can say</text><text start="2954.045" dur="5.168">“ok what is your problem?” and by
hearing what their problem is you</text><text start="2959.214" dur="4.791">can then create a picture in your
mind so you know what they need</text><text start="2964.006" dur="6.926">to be free. For example, if somebody come
and say, Ouf, I really have a problem</text><text start="2970.933" dur="5.292">with porn. I have been seeing a lot of
porn on the internet and I feel addicted</text><text start="2976.226" dur="7.342">to it and it&amp;#39;s really hard. In some case
it can be every thing. It can be a renewal</text><text start="2983.569" dur="4.378">of the mind that need to take place.
It can also be unclean spirit and</text><text start="2987.948" dur="2.816">deliverance need to take place.</text><text start="2990.765" dur="6.1">If I meet a person who have that,
the question is first, the gospel.</text><text start="2996.866" dur="6.816">Have you repented? Or do you just live
in sin with many other things also?</text><text start="3003.683" dur="4.468">Or is it just that thing that is not easy to let go?
Have you repented and have</text><text start="3008.152" dur="5.484">you got a new heart? Question? Have
got baptised in water after you</text><text start="3013.637" dur="4.867">repented? And have you
received the Holy Spirit?</text><text start="3018.505" dur="5.267">Because the bible says again as I
said last time the one who does sin</text><text start="3023.773" dur="5.509">becomes a slave to sin. He had now
seen a lot of porn on the internet</text><text start="3029.283" dur="5.048">and became a slave to it. What
he needs of course is to repent.</text><text start="3034.332" dur="5.969">But he also needs to bury the old body.
He needed to get rid of that old</text><text start="3040.302" dur="6.053">body that was bound to sin and in those
cases I have seen many people come and</text><text start="3046.356" dur="5.763">have been bound to sin and when they get
baptised in water and come out again they</text><text start="3052.12" dur="6.014">are free or it is leaving them right away.
So I would ask ‘what about this?</text><text start="3058.135" dur="4.396">What about this?, what about this?
And if he says ‘I have repented I</text><text start="3062.532" dur="5.094">have been baptised in water, I have the
Holy Spirit, I speak in tongues. Then I</text><text start="3067.627" dur="3.49">would say ok’ let’s pray and
see what happens. And then</text><text start="3071.118" dur="5.082">I would take his hand and then lead
him to a prayer of repentance.</text><text start="3076.201" dur="2.683">‘I don’t know if it is a spirit,
I don’t know if it is just a</text><text start="3078.885" dur="4.061">renewing of the mind, so I work with
everything at the same time. So I lead</text><text start="3082.947" dur="5.308">him into a prayer of repentance and
as soon as he has prayed a prayer and</text><text start="3088.256" dur="4.279">asked for forgiveness I would just speak
speak as if there was a demon, I would</text><text start="3092.536" dur="3.955">then say “you unclean spirit go right now”
“I command you unclean spirit go right</text><text start="3096.492" dur="4.213">now, go right now, go right now!” “I
command this spirit, unclean spirit,</text><text start="3100.706" dur="4.269">the spirit of addiction the spirit
of porn I command you spirit come</text><text start="3104.976" dur="5.727">out of him! leave him right now!” And I
would speak like there is something.</text><text start="3110.704" dur="8.249">After a few seconds or fifteen seconds
he starts to breath quicker and he start</text><text start="3118.954" dur="4.608">to breathe and he start to manifest so
you therefore see there is a spirit and</text><text start="3123.563" dur="5.639">then you command until he is coughing
and it&amp;#39;s out of there ‘deep exhale’</text><text start="3129.203" dur="4.318">and something left him. I would
have to say ‘now it is gone.</text><text start="3133.522" dur="2.079">But now you have to
renew your mind.</text><text start="3135.602" dur="4.661">Take Romans 6, read it again
and say ‘I am free from sin.</text><text start="3140.264" dur="3.748">Sin has no more dominion over
me anymore…and so on and so on.</text><text start="3144.013" dur="5.593">This is how I would deal with him or if
I pray for him and nothing manifests</text><text start="3149.607" dur="6.271">then I say ok I don’t think it is a demon
because we have authority and I spoke</text><text start="3155.879" dur="4.894">and nothing happened so therefore I
think you just have to renew your mind</text><text start="3160.774" dur="5.277">You have to understand you are free.
And then I would encourage him to</text><text start="3166.052" dur="5.41">read Romans 6 and pray about it
when he gets that understanding of</text><text start="3171.463" dur="3.542">what it is and there he will experience
freedom, this is one example.</text><text start="3175.006" dur="6.839">Another example ‘a woman came to me
and she said “I have a problem with</text><text start="3181.846" dur="7.627">an eating disorder, I have a problem with
that” ‘ok’ how did it start? I often ask</text><text start="3189.474" dur="5.131">that, ‘how did it start? And then you
actually find out the eating disorder is</text><text start="3194.606" dur="7.373">not the main problem…the eating disorder
is just the fruit of the main problem.</text><text start="3201.98" dur="5.224">The main problem maybe was ‘a problem
with her parents, that she has</text><text start="3207.205" dur="4.761">unforgiveness towards them because she
is hurt or she experienced something</text><text start="3211.967" dur="5.384">in school or somebody teased her. So
I have a problem but I want to go to</text><text start="3217.352" dur="7.192">the root of the problem and when it is
like that I know that it can be demonic,</text><text start="3224.545" dur="6.337">it maybe starts up as a hurt and
bitterness and unforgiveness but it can</text><text start="3230.883" dur="5.068">open the door to something that is
demonic so I would again ask her what</text><text start="3235.976" dur="2.497">about the gospel first, ‘have you repented?
Have you been baptised</text><text start="3238.474" dur="3.377">in water and the Holy Spirit? ‘if
not I would actually just sit down</text><text start="3241.852" dur="4.593">and go through the gospel with her
and then take it all right away.</text><text start="3246.446" dur="5.764">‘If that is ok I would then say ok’
are you ready to forgive those</text><text start="3252.267" dur="4.04">people who hurt you? Are
you ready to let go?</text><text start="3256.308" dur="4.715">Why? Because I don’t know if it is a
demon and I don’t know if it is renewing</text><text start="3261.024" dur="4.825">the mind and no matter what I want to work
with the full freedom, I want to work</text><text start="3265.85" dur="3.601">with everything at the same time. If
it is just a demon they don’t need to</text><text start="3269.452" dur="8.519">forgive you can just cast out that demon
but if she has a problem with forgiveness</text><text start="3277.972" dur="5.715">then for her to really be free in her
mind she needs to forgive, I hope you</text><text start="3283.688" dur="5.475">understand it. So what do I do with her?
I would lead her through a prayer and</text><text start="3289.164" dur="3.454">say are you ready to forgive those people
who teach you in school are you ready to</text><text start="3292.619" dur="4.663">forgive your parents and let go? And if
she is I would take her hand and pray</text><text start="3297.283" dur="4.315">with her, lead her through a prayer
confession, I forgive those people who</text><text start="3301.599" dur="4.501">hurt me, I forgive my parents and then
as soon as I pray for her I say “let go,</text><text start="3306.166" dur="3.671">let go, let go, ‘freedom, freedom,
‘I speak to this demon I command</text><text start="3309.838" dur="3.479">this spirit to leave her right now, I
command this spirit to go right now</text><text start="3313.318" dur="4.743">in the name of Jesus!” and I would take
authority over that spirit of eating</text><text start="3318.062" dur="3.043">disorder and I would just say
it like ‘ eating disorder’.</text><text start="3321.106" dur="4.177">Like with Jesus there was a dumb spirit
and he said ‘dumb spirit’ come out’,</text><text start="3325.284" dur="4.869">here the problem is ‘eating disorder’
Eating disorder come out! If her</text><text start="3330.154" dur="3.979">problem is depression, ‘Depression come out!
If her problem is fear,</text><text start="3334.134" dur="4.184">‘Fear come out! So every time I
meet somebody who needs healing for</text><text start="3338.343" dur="4.423">freedom or counselling session or
something ‘I would say “what is your</text><text start="3342.823" dur="4.669">problem?” and if they say the problem is
‘this, this, this, this… so I create a</text><text start="3347.493" dur="5.291">picture, so these are those problems,
‘it could be renewing the mind,</text><text start="3352.785" dur="3.215">casting out demons, and there
is power in the gospel.</text><text start="3356.382" dur="3.98">So I would then talk with her
and lead her through prayer,</text><text start="3360.387" dur="4.18">‘repentance, forgiveness or I share
the gospel with her and then I</text><text start="3364.592" dur="4.009">would take authority and in many cases
the sooner you take authority and</text><text start="3368.634" dur="4.785">command that demon to go, ‘what happens
they start to manifest because</text><text start="3373.444" dur="5.127">the demon is going. Sometimes you
command that demon to go and nothing</text><text start="3378.596" dur="4.407">is happening and then say ‘I don’t see
there is a demon lets continue with</text><text start="3383.028" dur="5.627">renewing the mind lets continue with
understanding who you are in Christ</text><text start="3388.68" dur="6.193">because it doesn’t look like it&amp;#39;s a demon.
So this is some of the things I often do</text><text start="3395.341" dur="9.445">when it comes to this, another example
‘somebody is addicted to smoking ‘again’</text><text start="3404.787" dur="5.625">I have met many people who got set free
by renewing the mind and by coming to</text><text start="3410.413" dur="4.375">that knowledge that this is a sin they
need to let go of, but I have also met</text><text start="3414.813" dur="5.361">people where we need to pray into it
and command that spirit of addiction</text><text start="3420.239" dur="6.852">to go and by coughing something
out they are free. So everything</text><text start="3427.092" dur="3.917">as I see it like Jesus healed a blind guy.
Sometimes He just healed it,</text><text start="3431.01" dur="6.207">sometimes he cast out a demon,
so every sickness and addiction</text><text start="3437.218" dur="2.712">it can be a renewing
of the mind and</text><text start="3439.955" dur="5.321">it can be a casting out a demon
and in many cases the gospel is</text><text start="3445.301" dur="3.829">taking it all, because in the gospel
there is the renewing of the mind and</text><text start="3449.131" dur="4.939">repentance. There is ‘burying the old life
in water and there is the Holy Spirit and</text><text start="3454.071" dur="4.659">power to live the new life. Another
thing before I am going to talk</text><text start="3458.731" dur="4.622">about my old life and come with some
examples there, when we talk about</text><text start="3463.354" dur="4.918">casting out demons I think it&amp;#39;s important
for people to understand what is the</text><text start="3468.273" dur="4.655">normal life? Because I meet people who
come to me and think that they have a</text><text start="3472.929" dur="4.231">lot of problems with demons but actually
they don’t have a lot of problems they</text><text start="3477.161" dur="6.188">are just human, they are just normal, for
example often when I have a meeting I</text><text start="3483.35" dur="4.415">use this example ‘sometimes when I am out
driving I can get a thought in my head</text><text start="3487.766" dur="7.809">&amp;quot;What would happen if I drive on the other
side into water, into a big truck?’</text><text start="3495.576" dur="4.722">I can get that thought, &amp;quot;But
if I am out having a meeting</text><text start="3500.299" dur="3.403">and I ask “how many
sometimes get that thought?</text><text start="3503.703" dur="4.225">It is maybe 30% – 40% who
sometimes think that.</text><text start="3507.929" dur="5.225">It is not a big issue for me and it is not
a big issue for most people because we</text><text start="3513.155" dur="5.916">know when we get a thought, we ignore it,
because we know we are not going to do it</text><text start="3519.072" dur="4.503">We are free not to do it. But there are
people who are so afraid of demon, demon,</text><text start="3523.576" dur="4.319">demon, demon…thinking there is demons
everywhere and when they get the same</text><text start="3527.896" dur="3.913">thought then they run to meeting after
meeting and say “Pray for me, pray for me</text><text start="3531.81" dur="3.335">I have an attack…demons help me, what
is wrong with me, I have that thought!”</text><text start="3535.146" dur="4.828">I have an attack…demons, help me, what
is wrong with me, I have that thought!”</text><text start="3539.975" dur="1.2">And they often think that they have big
issues, it&amp;#39;s not that they don’t have a</text><text start="3541.176" dur="3.913">big issue. It’s that they are just human,
because we are living in a world here</text><text start="3545.09" dur="2.046">where we have problems</text><text start="3547.137" dur="4.846">and where we would get different
thoughts and we would be tempted ‘but’,</text><text start="3551.984" dur="7.031">freedom is; ‘freedom‘not’ to
do what we are tempted to do’.</text><text start="3559.76" dur="4.062">So what is the normal life of a christian?
There are some people who think that</text><text start="3563.847" dur="4.369">the Christian life is like this (image of
straight line) it is like you start your</text><text start="3568.241" dur="2.59">christian walk (beginning of line) and
straight to the end….it is so easy.</text><text start="3571.329" dur="4.659">This is ‘not’ how it is, it is maybe how
it is before you become a Christian but</text><text start="3576.014" dur="2.425">when you become a Christian (opposite
image) it looks more like this (dip and</text><text start="3579.358" dur="6.323">high points) I would say this is how my
life is, ‘I experience attacks, attacks,</text><text start="3586.348" dur="4.333">attacks, and a big! Attack and a
breakthough…another attack, attack,</text><text start="3590.707" dur="2.804">attacksand a big! Attack and
breakthrough a lot of attacks.</text><text start="3594.082" dur="5.765">And I think this is often how we live as
Christians, and try to imagine if I am</text><text start="3599.872" dur="5.568">laying in a hospital right now and I have
a ‘cardiogram on me and this is how my</text><text start="3605.986" dur="6.694">heart is showing mmeeeeeeeeet! (straight
line) if this is cardiogram at a</text><text start="3612.705" dur="5.183">hospital ‘showing how my heart is ‘I am dead!
My heart should look more like</text><text start="3617.913" dur="5.596">this (dips and high points) The
same way I would say to people if</text><text start="3623.534" dur="5.914">your life is like this ‘you are dead’ you
need to become alive with Jesus, you</text><text start="3629.473" dur="5.662">need to live for him because as soon
as you become alive for Jesus, ‘I am</text><text start="3635.16" dur="3.202">going to talk about that in some of the
other programmes about the attacks</text><text start="3638.473" dur="5.003">you will experience crazy
attacks, crazy attacks’.</text><text start="3643.889" dur="5.602">Story, some of you have heard the
story how I met my wife, the story if</text><text start="3649.516" dur="3.134">you don’t know it, after I became a Christian.
I was at a Christian concert</text><text start="3652.674" dur="4.145">and there I heard God spoke to me he said
“Torben”, and I was like ‘yea’, “the</text><text start="3656.918" dur="4.381">one standing behind you, she is going
to be your wife some day and I was like</text><text start="3661.324" dur="5.137">&amp;quot;Wow&amp;quot; and I turned around and I saw her!
I just knew it was my wife! It was the</text><text start="3666.486" dur="4.818">one God had for me. I only smiled at her,
jumped into the car, went home. I said to</text><text start="3671.329" dur="4.268">my friend on my way home “Hey Michael! I
have just met my wife!” “I don’t know</text><text start="3675.622" dur="3.288">her name?, I don’t know where she is from?
I don’t know how old she is? But God</text><text start="3678.935" dur="3.385">“has said that girl in that dress
is some day going to be my wife”.</text><text start="3682.346" dur="5.492">I came home to my old city, and said “God
you have to put me together with her.</text><text start="3687.863" dur="3.038">I don’t know where she is from? three
months later He put us together</text><text start="3690.926" dur="2.667">and now we have been married
20 years and have three kids.</text><text start="3693.851" dur="3.544">It was very short how I met my
wife, many have heard that story</text><text start="3697.835" dur="2.309">but many have not
heard another story.</text><text start="3700.681" dur="6.992">Some years later after we were married I
experienced some of those attacks, and</text><text start="3707.698" dur="7.035">one day it came to my head like almost the
same voice as I heard many years before</text><text start="3715.463" dur="7.392">‘Leave your wife, leave your kids, go out
in the world.’ ‘What! ‘Leave your wife,</text><text start="3722.919" dur="4.301">leave your kids and go out in the world’.
And it just came to me in my head!</text><text start="3727.258" dur="5.344">Leave your wife, leave your kids..go…! ”No!
No! I love Lene! I love my kids!…..</text><text start="3732.626" dur="4.08">I love you Jesus!” I am not going to live
in sin, I am not going to leave you!” ……</text><text start="3736.731" dur="4.006">&amp;quot;Leave your wife, leave your kids go out
into the world.&amp;quot; Suddenly it was like</text><text start="3740.762" dur="4.665">somebody in my head was speaking
to me that I should leave my wife,</text><text start="3745.475" dur="2.132">leave my kids and go out in the world.
But I knew the word of God,</text><text start="3747.608" dur="4.204">and I took the word and I said,
“God, what you have put together,</text><text start="3751.813" dur="3.578">no man shall divide. Go away satan,
in the name of Jesus.&amp;quot; And I went on</text><text start="3755.392" dur="4.41">praying and praying against it.
But it was like nothing had</text><text start="3759.803" dur="3.462">happened. It was just in my head!
My head! My head!</text><text start="3763.688" dur="5.308">What then? I prayed. I said it to
my wife &amp;quot;Pray for me, pray for me…</text><text start="3769.021" dur="3.261">&amp;quot;I feel I should leave you and
the kids and I don’t want it.</text><text start="3772.307" dur="2.721">I pray God, pray for me, pray
for me… I feel an attack!</text><text start="3775.201" dur="4.865">After three days that thing just left!
And I was clear in my head again,</text><text start="3780.668" dur="3.429">and I did not understand why did I
experience something like that?</text><text start="3784.479" dur="3.814">A few days later I was at a meeting
where I got a prophecy and the</text><text start="3788.318" dur="3.882">prophecy was that many have come to
that point where I was now but have</text><text start="3792.225" dur="5.517">fallen and I should do this and this and
this and when I got the prophecy suddenly</text><text start="3797.768" dur="6.242">I understood something, before that I
sometimes never understood how can</text><text start="3804.035" dur="4.133">people first experience Jesus and then fall away?
But now I understood’</text><text start="3808.291" dur="6.338">‘we are in a war’ we are in a spiritual
war’ and therefore people fall away.</text><text start="3814.719" dur="5.81">And Ephesians 6, talks about putting on
the armour of God the helmet of salvation</text><text start="3820.554" dur="6.967">to help us through those attacks, the
shield of faith and so on. So I there</text><text start="3827.546" dur="6.562">experienced an attack, it did not mean
I had a demon, it just means that I am</text><text start="3834.133" dur="5.103">alive for God so it does not mean I have
run to a meeting and ask ‘pray for me,</text><text start="3839.261" dur="4.18">pray for me I have a demon’ inside, ‘no
it’s not an attack from inside, it is an</text><text start="3843.466" dur="5.124">attack from outside. And sometimes
there is people who think</text><text start="3848.615" dur="4.508">they have a lot of demons but they don’t
have a lot of demons, they just have the</text><text start="3853.142" dur="6.298">wrong focus and they think that …they take
the small attacks they experience and</text><text start="3859.441" dur="6.134">then they paint it up to be something big!
And that is why I sometimes use</text><text start="3865.6" dur="3.344">this example when I talk to people about
deliverance and say “come on, there is</text><text start="3869.097" dur="4">nothing wrong with you that your life
looks like this (dips and highs) it</text><text start="3873.122" dur="3.824">doesn’t mean you have a lot of demons,
this just means that you are taking new</text><text start="3876.971" dur="3.547">steps in faith and God is with
you, and satan hates you.</text><text start="3881.239" dur="8.091">So, ok about freedom, my life I will try
to take a person and talk about my life</text><text start="3889.355" dur="5.452">about how I experienced freedom and then
I will pray for all of you out there.</text><text start="3895.41" dur="5.305">How I experienced my freedom, my life
was good up until that day. I got born</text><text start="3900.74" dur="7.266">and then the problems started because
when I got born 40 years ago I had many</text><text start="3908.031" dur="4.75">problems in my life, one of the problems
was I had a speech problem, I could not</text><text start="3912.806" dur="4.2">pronounce my own name. When I was
younger my name was Torben Sondergaard</text><text start="3917.031" dur="4.442">it is still Torben Sondergaard but I said
‘Gorben Goonergaur I couldn’t pronounce</text><text start="3921.498" dur="4.709">my own name, and it was only my brother
who understood me when I was really young</text><text start="3926.232" dur="7.921">so when I went to school, when my school
class had teaching I was very often</text><text start="3934.178" dur="5.863">sitting in another room with somebody
teaching me to pronounce words and to</text><text start="3940.066" dur="6.678">speak, and I tried to pronounce words
‘G, G,G, …..and it was not easy for me.</text><text start="3947.514" dur="6.35">At the same time I could not read and
write and I actually had problems with</text><text start="3953.889" dur="3.658">that and I also was not together with
my class I was sitting in another room</text><text start="3957.572" dur="4.451">with somebody who was helping me to
read and write and I got checked and</text><text start="3962.048" dur="5.274">they tried to see if everything was
ok but I was just not good at it.</text><text start="3967.347" dur="4.924">At the same time I was the fat boy in the
class, I was the boy who after school</text><text start="3972.296" dur="4.313">bought a bag of chips and a coke on
my way home and watched tv the whole</text><text start="3976.634" dur="4.275">afternoon and evening and the
day after, and the day after.</text><text start="3980.934" dur="6.356">So you know if you cannot read, if you
cannot write, if you are a big boy,</text><text start="3987.315" dur="3.763">if you have problems speaking and you
are not together with the rest of</text><text start="3991.079" dur="6.459">the class you get teased a lot. So I got
teased and I was one of those who went</text><text start="3997.539" dur="6.821">home crying a lot after school and dreamt
about something else. When I left school</text><text start="4004.361" dur="6.095">I had no self-confidence at all and I had
a lot of hurt inside because of what I</text><text start="4010.457" dur="5.845">experienced, then I left school and took
one year on another school and I hope</text><text start="4016.327" dur="6.43">maybe I can change myself here because
I hated who I was, but when I left to</text><text start="4022.758" dur="4.741">another school I could see I could not
change myself I was the one I was, I</text><text start="4027.5" dur="6.077">could not change who I was. So I came
in the old thing again and I got teased</text><text start="4033.578" dur="4.666">and it was not easy for me. What
happened then was ‘at that time</text><text start="4038.269" dur="7.272">I was 15 – 16 years old, I would say my
mum meant a lot to me, I was my mum’s</text><text start="4045.566" dur="5.46">boy because when I got teased a lot my
mum understood me ‘she was good to me,</text><text start="4051.146" dur="6.363">she loved me a lot’. My father was a good
man but he had his own business, I did not</text><text start="4057.534" dur="5.602">have a close relationship with him,
so my mum meant everything to me.</text><text start="4063.753" dur="6.133">What happened there was ‘my mum one day
when I was 16 years old, she got a</text><text start="4069.911" dur="5.896">stroke and she got paralysed and was
almost dying again, and again and again,</text><text start="4075.832" dur="5.339">so suddenly I lost my mum, suddenly and
next time I saw her she ‘yes’ she was</text><text start="4081.196" dur="5.832">without hair laying in a hospital bed and
it did something I me, it really hurt me!</text><text start="4087.053" dur="5.828">It created some hurt inside of me! I
remember when I was 16 years old she</text><text start="4092.979" dur="3.375">was lying in a hospital bed and I was
alone with her and she was paralysed</text><text start="4096.354" dur="7.129">now and she had a respirator helping her
to breath and she started to come to</text><text start="4103.484" dur="4.606">herself and speak a little and she tried
to take the respirator off her body,</text><text start="4109.022" dur="4.373">and I was standing there saying ‘mum
no don’t do it’ and she tried it</text><text start="4113.42" dur="4.501">again and I said ‘mum don’t do it’ and
she tried it again, and then I heard her</text><text start="4117.955" dur="7.242">say with a big voice “let go!” “or I
kill you!” and I remember still like</text><text start="4125.221" dur="6.783">it was yesterday. When she said those
words ‘let go, I kill you’ it was like a</text><text start="4132.029" dur="7.222">knife just came into my body and killed me.
Something just broke inside of me.</text><text start="4140.604" dur="6.277">And she was at the hospital just one and a
half year and at that time I got hurt a</text><text start="4146.979" dur="8.213">lot and later, a few years later I got a
girlfriend and she was unfaithful to me</text><text start="4155.216" dur="4.44">and I was unfaithful to her and I got
hurt because of that and she because of</text><text start="4159.68" dur="9.018">what I did, so when I was 18 years old I
had ‘no’ self -confidence, I could not</text><text start="4168.723" dur="5.915">read or write, I read one small book in
my whole life, I had a lot of hurt from</text><text start="4174.662" dur="5.116">my mum, because with my mum’s thing
it built a big wall around me</text><text start="4179.803" dur="5.335">because I got hurt, and when you get hurt
you build a wall around you to protect you</text><text start="4185.162" dur="4.605">from getting hurt again, so nobody could
come close to me. Nobody could talk about</text><text start="4189.792" dur="4.815">emotion and feeling, I had really big
problems with that I was always making</text><text start="4194.648" dur="5.479">fun or pushing people away as soon as
they came close to me I did not believe</text><text start="4200.128" dur="3.374">in love at that time because of
my girlfriend ‘I got hurt there.</text><text start="4203.503" dur="6.655">So as 18 years old it was my life, a
lot of problems, no self-confidence,</text><text start="4210.159" dur="4.712">had a hurt when it came to relationship,
mum and dad, and did not believe in love.</text><text start="4215.069" dur="4.735">But then ‘God came’ ‘Da’ Daa!
The Holy Spirit came in!</text><text start="4219.829" dur="3.989">And when the Holy Spirit came in,
God came, the first thing that</text><text start="4223.843" dur="6.929">happened was that I just knew ‘nothing!
Is impossible for those</text><text start="4230.797" dur="4.064">who believe. Nothing is impossible!
Something just grew inside of me</text><text start="4234.886" dur="4.201">and I just knew everything is now
possible this was the first thing</text><text start="4239.112" dur="4.208">I experienced. Second thing I experienced
in the gospel I got set free from the</text><text start="4243.345" dur="7.354">spirit of death, I was so afraid of dying
but when the gospel came in that fear</text><text start="4250.724" dur="6.851">of dying just went away and something
happened to me and then God started</text><text start="4257.6" dur="4.355">to heal me, to set me free. My
life was not a lot of deliverance,</text><text start="4261.98" dur="4.345">my life was spending time with
God and seeing healing by that.</text><text start="4266.678" dur="3.938">At one time the Holy Spirit came in and I
just started to cry, ‘I was crying, every</text><text start="4270.641" dur="5.36">time I was at a meeting I was crying,
and crying and crying and people came</text><text start="4276.026" dur="2.703">and said (people)“are you good Torben?”
“are you ok?” (Torben) “yes…I am…</text><text start="4278.754" dur="2.485">(people) “why are you crying?”
(Torben) “I don’t know”….</text><text start="4281.448" dur="2.616">But why was I crying? ‘I
was crying because some of</text><text start="4284.089" dur="4.4">the hurt with my mum and dad,
some of the hurt came out and</text><text start="4288.933" dur="5.617">I believe I went through a healing
or deliverance there without anybody</text><text start="4294.575" dur="3.968">praying for me but just spending
time with God and renewing my mind</text><text start="4298.568" dur="5.015">the healing started and God
he started to set me free.</text><text start="4304.469" dur="10.943">One of the things that really set me free
was LOVE, love, because what I have seen</text><text start="4315.437" dur="5.241">is not just about the gospel, healing the
sick, casting out demons, it is really</text><text start="4320.703" dur="5.286">the ‘LOVE’ and people need to experience
the love, the love of God and the love of</text><text start="4326.014" dur="8.229">the church. Because what was interesting
with me, after I met my wife Lene,</text><text start="4335.495" dur="6.894">I remember one time I met somebody ‘my
father in-law he became my spiritual</text><text start="4342.413" dur="4.024">father, he was an amazing guy, Lene’s
father is an amazing guy who had</text><text start="4346.462" dur="3.558">a church at home so he became my
spiritual father when I got born again</text><text start="4350.046" dur="6.116">and helped me and was there in the
beginning a lot and what was amazing</text><text start="4356.187" dur="6.22">was when they took me to some friends,
and I remember I was a young boy,</text><text start="4362.432" dur="4.197">new in the faith and I came into that
house and there was a big guy living in</text><text start="4366.653" dur="5.124">that house and I put my hand out to say
‘Hi.’ But when I put out my hand to say</text><text start="4371.802" dur="6.226">&amp;#39;Hi&amp;#39;, he just said “Hi and gave me a BIG hug!
And I was standing like this (shock!)</text><text start="4378.403" dur="7.008">I was standing like this (in shock) when
he hugged me, It was so weird for me</text><text start="4385.569" dur="4.081">and I remember I sat down on a chair
afterward and looked at this man’</text><text start="4391.686" dur="6.338">(weird….moving away) ‘who is he?
‘he touched me? He hugged me?</text><text start="4398.81" dur="6.977">It felt so weird because I was not used
to that, we did not touch each other in</text><text start="4405.812" dur="4.645">our family, we did not hug each other,
we did not talk a lot about love and</text><text start="4410.482" dur="5.341">emotions and I was not used to that
when he hugged me it felt somehow</text><text start="4415.848" dur="9.728">weird but it felt good. It felt like ‘I
need that’ I need a strong man in my life</text><text start="4425.601" dur="5.152">who can be like a father who can give
me a hug and God there started to heal</text><text start="4430.778" dur="4.274">me and what I see that many people who
have issues in life actually have issues</text><text start="4435.077" dur="8.061">because of their parents of lack of that.
They have issues because they did not</text><text start="4443.163" dur="4.99">have a mum in their life who really could
give them what they needed and a mum</text><text start="4448.178" dur="9.566">is supposed to create security and safety
where you experience that, a father is</text><text start="4457.758" dur="6.302">supposed to create faith in you, you can
do it, come on climb tall as the tree, run</text><text start="4464.085" dur="3.916">faster, you can do it, more…you are cool!
You can do it, you are amazing!</text><text start="4468.026" dur="5.697">A father is supposed to create that
self confidence that you can do it.</text><text start="4473.916" dur="4.153">What our problem is in the world today
when we often counsel people and talk</text><text start="4478.094" dur="4.435">with people? is that people do not have
that father and mother in their life as I</text><text start="4482.553" dur="7.629">did not have like that who could create
that foundation and many people are hurt</text><text start="4490.207" dur="6.31">and have issues today that go down to that
so when I counsel people I often ask ‘how</text><text start="4496.542" dur="5.191">is your relationship with your mum and
your dad, and quite often we need to</text><text start="4501.758" dur="5.236">forgive, we need to forgive them and
sometimes we need to cast out demons</text><text start="4507.019" dur="5.08">and sometimes we just need to give people love.
Just give them a big hug.</text><text start="4512.222" dur="7.182">What happened for me was that God started,
I got that hug and got introduced</text><text start="4519.429" dur="5.085">to my family so we started to hug each
other in my family at home with my mum</text><text start="4524.539" dur="6.343">and dad because I somehow brought it in.
but there were things that was difficult</text><text start="4530.907" dur="4.946">for me. I remember a few years ago I was
in Moldova we were driving down there</text><text start="4535.878" dur="5.456">through Germany and Poland and Romania
and Moldova and it was a long</text><text start="4541.359" dur="5.797">trip and we felt we were far away and
we had been driving the whole way with</text><text start="4547.181" dur="3.865">my wife and family and we were going
to drive through Ukraine Home and so</text><text start="4551.071" dur="5.681">on so I wrote a letter to my parents I
wrote’ Hey mum and dad ‘everything is</text><text start="4556.777" dur="4.719">good, everything is good and so on and so
on…..see you later, and then I wrote in</text><text start="4561.521" dur="4.919">the end “I love you” normally I did not
write that but it only because I felt far</text><text start="4566.465" dur="4.977">away and I did not know if I was going
to survive, so I just wanted to let them</text><text start="4571.467" dur="4.6">know, and then they wrote back again.
Ah Torben! Thank you! thank you for</text><text start="4576.13" dur="5.907">your letter and especially the last three words!
‘we have read them again and</text><text start="4582.062" dur="5.995">again and again. And it meant so much to
my parents to hear me say that I love</text><text start="4588.082" dur="6.681">them. But when I came home I couldn’t say
it again I couldn’t say it again, it</text><text start="4594.788" dur="4.582">was so difficult, and I thought what is wrong?
Because I know I love my parents,</text><text start="4599.395" dur="7.115">why could I not say that I love them?
Maybe because I don’t remember when</text><text start="4606.535" dur="6.388">I heard my father say that he loves
me, and God started to work in me and</text><text start="4612.948" dur="4.918">especially the last years even when
we got the Jesus hotel and we started</text><text start="4617.891" dur="4.473">to travel because it is so interesting
when you travel you meet many cultures.</text><text start="4622.405" dur="4.819">The first time we came to Holland we
were saying ‘hello’ and people ‘kissed’</text><text start="4627.256" dur="4.976">in Holland like three times……kiss, kiss,
kiss and we were not used to that so the</text><text start="4632.257" dur="4.157">first time we were like oh? they are
kissing!, then we went other places,</text><text start="4636.439" dur="4.056">South Africa people kiss on the mouth there!!!
In some places!!! and the</text><text start="4640.52" dur="2.84">next time we met somebody (stretched
our hand out to them to try not to get</text><text start="4643.421" dur="4.833">close) “hello….Then there came a girl
here from Italy and I said ‘hello and</text><text start="4648.279" dur="4.172">she was ready to give me a kiss! And
I was thinking ‘oh no’ is it two or</text><text start="4652.476" dur="10.374">three times? It was only two times. But
one time at the Jesus hotel here we</text><text start="4662.875" dur="4.547">were standing with some of the young
people and I asked them ‘do you tell</text><text start="4667.447" dur="4.025">your parents that you love them?
(young people) ‘no…no, no, no</text><text start="4671.496" dur="2.68">(T) “Do you give hugs to people
at home?” (young people) ‘No’</text><text start="4674.529" dur="4.122">And many young people are not used
to that, many people are not used to</text><text start="4678.675" dur="8.634">talking about emotion, many people are not
used to that. So what did I do? I sat</text><text start="4687.334" dur="7.026">down and wrote a letter to my dad and said
“Father, it is so difficult for me to</text><text start="4694.385" dur="6.638">say I love you, and I don’t want it to
be like that, I just want to know that I</text><text start="4701.048" dur="5.205">don’t remember I if I heard it from you
‘and not to criticise but we are not used</text><text start="4706.278" dur="3.623">to that in our family, but I just
want to let you know that I love you.</text><text start="4710.587" dur="4.419">And normally he answered back but he
didn’t so I needed to call him after</text><text start="4715.031" dur="4.736">a few days and say did you get the letter?
‘yes thank you’ ‘but I don’t know what to</text><text start="4719.792" dur="5.843">answer?’ I said “oh, it’s ok” But I
went home and me and my father he</text><text start="4725.66" dur="6.867">is 78 for the first time ever I remember
we took a father, son walk and we talked</text><text start="4732.552" dur="7.397">about it and he said “Torben, about your
letter, yes, we were not used to hugging</text><text start="4739.974" dur="6.176">each other in our family and touching each
other and I have not said that I love you,</text><text start="4747.888" dur="6.435">because my father had never told me that
he loved me, I am not used to this.</text><text start="4754.949" dur="6.192">And for me to hear those words actually
did something to me because, it’s not</text><text start="4761.166" dur="5.164">because my parents don’t love me, but
they did not know how to say it.</text><text start="4767.309" dur="7.443">Because they were influenced themselves.
And there is truly a freedom in this and</text><text start="4774.777" dur="6.069">there is many of you who are seeing this
now who have the same issue, some of you</text><text start="4780.871" dur="4.256">were already touched when I spoke about
it, and you are thinking ‘this is me’</text><text start="4785.509" dur="3.61">‘my father was not there,
my mother was not there’.</text><text start="4789.396" dur="5.209">And what we often do when we talk about God
is that if God is our father, but then</text><text start="4794.63" dur="6.301">we take God down on a human level so if
we had a father who was not there who</text><text start="4800.956" dur="5.343">heart us or hit us or did not have time
for us we take God down and think God</text><text start="4806.324" dur="5.976">is like that, God doesn’t have time for
us, he doesn’t like us. But Jesus said,</text><text start="4812.325" dur="6.787">‘When you who are evil give your
kids good gifts how much more will</text><text start="4819.137" dur="5.215">your Father in heaven not give the Spirit
to those who ask him. So Jesus is saying</text><text start="4824.377" dur="5.383">that we here who are evil can do good
things but God who is in heaven, he is</text><text start="4829.785" dur="7.29">up there, he is so much stronger and
better, pure, and loving, like any father</text><text start="4837.1" dur="5.142">here on earth. And we should never
take God down on a human level and</text><text start="4842.267" dur="5.539">make him like our father was here. And
I would say when I started to talk</text><text start="4847.832" dur="6.149">about this there is many people who
need to forgive their parents. ‘Yes but</text><text start="4854.006" dur="4.624">they hurt me’ ‘they didn’t give me what I needed’.
“Yes forgive them”.</text><text start="4858.655" dur="6.339">There is so much power in forgiveness.
When Jesus hung on the cross he said</text><text start="4865.019" dur="3.369">“Father forgive them for they do not
know what they are doing” “We think</text><text start="4868.413" dur="3.603">of course we knew what they were
doing!” “They took Jesus..and put him</text><text start="4872.041" dur="6.152">on the cross!” No, they did not know it!
they were not free those Romans who put</text><text start="4878.218" dur="4.022">Jesus on the cross, they were not free,
they were influenced by the Romans,</text><text start="4882.265" dur="6.362">they were influenced by fear, and they
were influenced by a lot of lies, they did</text><text start="4888.652" dur="4.402">not know who Jesus really was otherwise
they would not have done it. So they did</text><text start="4893.079" dur="5.664">it influenced by other people, the
same way with your mum, with your dad,</text><text start="4899.306" dur="3.978">with people around us who have hurt us
in school, people who have mocked us,</text><text start="4903.309" dur="4.488">people who have stolen, people who have
done things, we can forgive them, why?</text><text start="4907.822" dur="5.274">Because they did not know what they were
doing, if your father, if your mother</text><text start="4913.121" dur="5.592">were free and were not influenced by sin
and this world and by a childhood where</text><text start="4918.916" dur="8.644">they also did not experience love, hugging
and forgiveness, if they were totally free</text><text start="4927.585" dur="3.71">they would have given you something else,
but you cannot give something you don’t</text><text start="4931.32" dur="9.271">have. And I would say that this is a big
part of healing, ‘a big part’ of freedom,</text><text start="4941.076" dur="4.701">where we talk about this and the body of
Christ, the church should be a family</text><text start="4945.802" dur="9.483">where we come in and give a big hug!
And experience that we are family,</text><text start="4955.339" dur="5.091">we are not members of a body or
member of a church, we are family,</text><text start="4960.431" dur="5.868">we love each other. And I say no matter
what look at me! Again I could not read,</text><text start="4966.3" dur="6.064">I could not write, I had a lot of
problems but God has set me free.</text><text start="4972.365" dur="5.058">My Father never told me as I remember
that he loved me, I had a hurt, my mum</text><text start="4977.424" dur="4.683">got saved I had a hurt but God set me
free and delivered me, and now I am a</text><text start="4982.108" dur="7.379">father for many people, there are young
girls and boys I feel I can be there, and</text><text start="4989.488" dur="4.151">sometimes we don’t need to talk a lot
we just need to give them a hug.</text><text start="4993.64" dur="6.42">Come on’ I believe in you’ I believe in you.
So I want to end this up ‘we have</text><text start="5000.061" dur="5.231">got authority to cast out demons, when
it&amp;#39;s a demon we don’t need to know a lot</text><text start="5005.293" dur="3.558">we just need to ‘say ‘come out in the
name of Jesus’ but sometimes it is not</text><text start="5008.852" dur="4.594">a demon or deliverance we need,
sometimes it is a renewing of the mind,</text><text start="5013.447" dur="4.951">sometimes it is the gospel, but very
often it is just ‘LOVE’. Love hides</text><text start="5018.399" dur="5.609">a multitude of sins, to come in and
experience family, experience love.</text><text start="5024.009" dur="5.906">If that is you, if I meet somebody and I
talk about those things, what I often say</text><text start="5030.436" dur="4.977">to them, who are you?, what is your background?
What has made you who</text><text start="5035.414" dur="4.267">you are? And now you have heard this
teaching, what has made you who you are?</text><text start="5039.682" dur="4.191">What is your story? Some would
say ‘oh I have a problem</text><text start="5043.898" dur="6.018">with my mum, or my father, or I lost a
friend who died many years ago, I still</text><text start="5049.917" dur="7.231">hurt, I got teased in school and it opened
me up for something, I live in hard sin</text><text start="5057.15" dur="4.731">many years ago and I’ve never been able
to let go or I have a problem with this,</text><text start="5061.882" dur="2.744">I have a problem with a sickness, and it
came in like this and I have a problem</text><text start="5064.627" dur="5.438">with this, this…. By hearing
people telling their story they</text><text start="5070.066" dur="5.995">know ok, ‘do we start with the gospel,
do we start with casting out demons or</text><text start="5076.062" dur="3.238">maybe we start with renewing the mind
or maybe it is everything at the same</text><text start="5079.301" dur="5.702">time? Maybe they just need to forgive
their parents and we pray over them,</text><text start="5085.004" dur="5.715">and we command every hurt, every spirit
of unforgiveness and every hurt to leave,</text><text start="5090.72" dur="6.792">and then they cry and we give them a hug
and there is freedom and healing there and</text><text start="5097.513" dur="4.28">very often we did it here with the students
here at the Pioneer Training School a few</text><text start="5101.794" dur="4.262">days ago I talked about this and there
were people who broke down crying and</text><text start="5106.057" dur="6.239">so on, and very often something is
starting there like when my mum got</text><text start="5112.297" dur="4.172">sick I could not cry for years, I was not
able to cry but when the Holy Spirit came</text><text start="5116.47" dur="5.8">in I started to cry, cry, cry. And
that healing it took a few months</text><text start="5122.271" dur="5.068">before everything was out, when do we
know if a person is truly free? It is not</text><text start="5127.34" dur="5.709">always easy to see, sometimes we stand
in a place where we think maybe I need</text><text start="5133.074" dur="5.947">more freedom. Our focus is not ‘do I have problems?
Our focus is just doing the</text><text start="5139.046" dur="6.544">right thing, but sometimes things pop up,
and then we deal with it, we pray into it</text><text start="5145.591" dur="4.405">and we see what it is. Is it something
with the gospel we need? Is it the</text><text start="5150.021" dur="4.24">casting out of demons? or if it is the
renewing of the mind or what is it?</text><text start="5154.286" dur="4.977">I hope you got something out of this teaching.
It is a difficult teaching to</text><text start="5159.288" dur="6.044">do when I don’t know who you are who are
listening, if I saw you and you were</text><text start="5165.357" dur="4.544">standing in front of me right now
this is much more simple and so much</text><text start="5169.926" dur="4.781">more easier because then I would just ask
you’ who are you? what is your problem</text><text start="5174.732" dur="6.972">ok and then out of what you say I would
see if there is anybody you need to</text><text start="5181.729" dur="7.079">forgive? ‘ok’ is there anything you need to repent for?
‘ok&amp;#39; have you been baptised</text><text start="5188.833" dur="3.85">in water? or have you received the Holy Spirit?
If not that is what you need, and</text><text start="5192.708" dur="6.411">then I would lead you to a prayer, take
your hands and get you to relax, and</text><text start="5199.144" dur="3.888">then I would pray a prayer with you where
you might confess after me, and say ‘God</text><text start="5203.057" dur="4.807">I come to you ‘take my mum and my dad and
I hand them over to you, I take this</text><text start="5207.889" dur="4.173">hurt and I lay it over to you, I repent,
I ask for forgiveness for my sins,</text><text start="5212.087" dur="4.49">I have sins, I have sinned, I need
forgiveness to set me free, set me free</text><text start="5217.755" dur="5.231">from this spirit of depression, or
what it is, and then I would pray for</text><text start="5223.708" dur="5.288">them and then when I pray for them as
soon as I say Amen, I say ‘Holy Spirit</text><text start="5229.021" dur="6.092">now it is you, And then I would speak, I
say “I speak to your hurt go right now,</text><text start="5235.138" dur="4.94">I speak to your hurt, unforgiveness with
your mum, dad go right now, spirit of</text><text start="5240.103" dur="3.336">unforgiveness go right now! Spirit of
depression go right now!, spirit of</text><text start="5243.464" dur="3.958">infirmity go right now! I speak to this
spirit of eating disorder, leave her,</text><text start="5247.447" dur="3.802">this pain go right now, just
speak, speak, speak, speak!</text><text start="5251.547" dur="4.254">And often something will happen, you don’t
close your eyes, you have your eyes</text><text start="5255.826" dur="4.44">open so you can see the manifestation,
what is happening, and sometimes you</text><text start="5260.291" dur="4.052">can just see them yawn, sometimes you
are not sure you ask, ‘is there more?</text><text start="5264.391" dur="3.433">Yes there is more’ or ‘no’….’I am free’,
and you pray for the Holy Spirit to fill</text><text start="5267.849" dur="5.597">them up. The best thing you can do is just
try to do it. The worst thing you can do is</text><text start="5273.471" dur="4.492">take this teaching and think ‘Oh no, it&amp;#39;s
too complicated! I don’t know when is</text><text start="5277.988" dur="5.746">that? ‘Just do it! ‘just go out and do it!
and you will learn by doing!</text><text start="5283.759" dur="5.518">Ok, the next teaching I will do in a few
weeks, I am going to Israel first and</text><text start="5289.302" dur="3.979">Jordan to have some meetings and then
after Israel, Jordan, we are going</text><text start="5293.306" dur="3.58">to do the next lesson on the Pioneer
School and maybe if there is some</text><text start="5296.911" dur="3.472">questions to this question I can
start with that in the next lesson.</text><text start="5300.891" dur="6.183">I will end up now, and hope you got something out
of this teaching and I will end up praying for you.</text><text start="5307.576" dur="2.599">You out there, now you
have listened to this.</text><text start="5310.882" dur="6.383">there is authority, I would like to pray for you, ‘are you
sick? Do you have sickness? Put your hand on the sick</text><text start="5317.29" dur="4.308">place, if you have pain in your heart
put your hand there, and I will pray</text><text start="5321.623" dur="3.252">with you and if you need to
forgive people who have hurt you,</text><text start="5324.9" dur="6.602">Then it is a decision, decide in your
heart you want to forgive them right now,</text><text start="5333.336" dur="4.821">and you pray with me, you pray and say“I
forgive them right now ‘I forgive</text><text start="5338.182" dur="5.108">my parents, my mum, my father what
they did, what they did not do, how</text><text start="5343.315" dur="5.512">they were not there, I let go of this
pain, I take this and I throw it on you</text><text start="5348.852" dur="4.01">Jesus and then I would pray for God
to come and the Holy Spirit, if you</text><text start="5352.887" dur="4.172">need more freedom and deliverance
go to our map and find somebody</text><text start="5357.084" dur="4.37">close to you because this is something
where people need too often</text><text start="5361.479" dur="4.253">sit down and do counselling and
you need somebody close to you</text><text start="5365.757" dur="3.473">who can do it or come to a
kick-start event or something else.</text><text start="5369.255" dur="3.734">I will pray now, God thank you for this
teaching, thank you for what you are</text><text start="5373.014" dur="4.112">doing, thank you because there is
freedom in you Jesus ‘I pray for those</text><text start="5377.151" dur="5.49">people who are sick in this right now
God I pray for freedom! Freedom to</text><text start="5382.665" dur="3.511">you right now in the name of Jesus every
hurt, every hurt in their heart that</text><text start="5386.201" dur="4.388">came through the mum, every hurt
when it comes to the dad, every hurt</text><text start="5390.614" dur="4.057">when it comes to being teased in school,
every hurt when it comes to bad</text><text start="5394.696" dur="4.246">experiences, I speak to this hurt, I
speak to this spirit of unbelief,</text><text start="5398.967" dur="3.575">unforgiveness, I speak to the spirit of
unforgiveness, I command the spirit to</text><text start="5402.567" dur="5.415">go right now, right now in the name of
Jesus, I speak to this hurt ‘go right now!</text><text start="5408.007" dur="5.938">I speak to this sickness this unclean
spirit I command you leave that person</text><text start="5413.97" dur="4.662">right now! I speak freedom! And I speak life!
In the name of Jesus I command you</text><text start="5418.657" dur="4.726">demon go right now! You unclean spirit go!
Go right now! You spirit of infirmity</text><text start="5423.408" dur="5.306">go right now in the name of Jesus! I speak
to you spirit of depression, spirit of</text><text start="5428.739" dur="5.757">fear! Go right now! In the name of Jesus!
I command freedom! In the name of Jesus</text><text start="5434.521" dur="6.79">and I ask you God come with your Holy
Spirit right now….(tongues) come with</text><text start="5441.336" dur="3.916">your Holy Spirit right now and fill
that person up, God come with your Holy</text><text start="5445.277" dur="4.079">Spirit God and if they need the gospel,
if they need to repent and get baptised</text><text start="5449.381" dur="3.595">Holy Spirit come and convince them,
convince them that this is what they</text><text start="5453.001" dur="4.146">need, open their eyes God, and pray
they are going to experience the same</text><text start="5457.172" dur="4.305">freedom I and thousands of other
people have experienced in you,</text><text start="5461.502" dur="5.394">so come Holy Spirit speak to them
touch them right now! In the name</text><text start="5466.921" dur="5.344">of Jesus. Amen. Come on guys. I
hope you got something out of it.</text><text start="5472.29" dur="4.028">I know it was a little long teaching
A lot of information. You&amp;#39;re welcome</text><text start="5476.343" dur="4.478">to see this teaching more times so you
really understand it and get it under</text><text start="5480.846" dur="4.717">skin. Until next time. God bless you.
Good-bye.</text><text start="5485.563" dur="1.437">Subtitles by the Amara.org community</text></transcript>